<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>The Virgin of the Sun on SWAGGERWORDS</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/tags/the-virgin-of-the-sun/</link>
        <description>Recent content in The Virgin of the Sun on SWAGGERWORDS</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://swaggerwords.win/en/tags/the-virgin-of-the-sun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>#01 Dedication and Introductory - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep01/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep01/</guid>
        <description>The Project Gutenberg eBook of The Virgin of the Sun
This ebook is for the use of anyone anywhere in the United States and most other parts of the world at no cost and with almost no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg License included with this ebook or online at www.gutenberg.org. If you are not located in the United States, you will have to check the laws of the country where you are located before using this eBook.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#02 The Sword and the Ring - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep02/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep02/</guid>
        <description>BOOK I
CHAPTER I
THE SWORD AND THE RING
I, Hubert of Hastings, write this in the land of Tavantinsuyu, far from England, where I was born, whither I shall never more return, being a wanderer as the rune upon the sword of my ancestor, Thorgrimmer, foretold that I should be, which sword my mother gave me on the day of the burning of Hastings by the French. I write it with a pen that I have shaped from a wing feather of the great eagle of the mountains, with ink that I have made from the juices of certain herbs which I discovered, and on parchment that I have split from the skins of native sheep, with my own hands, but badly I fear, though I have seen that art practised when I was a merchant of the Cheap in London Town.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#03 The Lady Blanche - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep03/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep03/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER II
THE LADY BLANCHE
So I went, with a sore heart, for I remembered that when my father and brothers were drowned, although I was then but a little one, my mother had foreseen it, and I feared much lest it might be thus in her own case also. I loved my mother. She was a stern woman, it was true, with little softness about her, which I think came with her blood, but she had a high heart, and oh!</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#04 Hubert Comes to London - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep04/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep04/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER III
HUBERT COMES TO LONDON
When the lady Blanche was out of sight, followed by the women who had sheltered with us in the cave, William and I went to a stream we knew of not far away and drank our fill. Then we walked to the three whom I had shot with my big bow, hoping to regain the arrows, for I had none left. This, however, could not be done though all the men were dead, for one of the shafts, the last, was broken, and the other two were so fixed in flesh and bone that only a surgeon’s saw would loose them.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#05 Kari - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep05/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep05/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER IV
KARI
Thus began my life in London in the house of my uncle, John Grimmer, who was called the Goldsmith. In truth, however, he was more than this, since not only did he fashion and trade in costly things; he lent out moneys to interest upon security to great people who needed it, and even to the king Richard and his Court. Also he owned ships and did much commerce with Holland, France, yes, and with Spain and Italy.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#06 The Coming of Blanche - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep06/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep06/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER V
THE COMING OF BLANCHE
One day, it was the last of the year, the anniversary of the death of my uncle whose goodness and wisdom I pondered on more and more as time went by, having a little time to spare from larger affairs, I chanced to be in the shop in the front of the house, which, as John Grimmer had said, he kept as a trap to “snare the ladybirds,” and I continued, because I knew that he would not wish that anything should be changed.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#07 Marriage and After - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep07/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep07/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER VI
MARRIAGE—AND AFTER
Sir Robert and I stood facing each other speechless with rage, both of us. At length he said in a hoarse voice:
“Your pardon, Master Hastings, for the affronts that this bastard lordling has put upon you, an honest man. I tell you that he is a loose-living knave, as you would agree if you knew all his story, a cockatrice that for my sins I have nurtured in my bosom.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#08 Book 2 Ch 1 The New World - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep08/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep08/</guid>
        <description>BOOK II
CHAPTER I
THE NEW WORLD
They were forever silent now, who, but a breath before, had been so full of life and the stir of mortal passion; Deleroy dead beneath the cloak upon the floor, Blanche dead in the oaken chair. We who remained alive were silent also. I glanced at Kari’s face; it was as that of a stone statue on a tomb, only in it his large eyes shone, noting all things and, as I imagined in my distraught fancy, filled with triumph and foreknowledge.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#09 Book 2 Ch 2 The Rocky Isle - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep09/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep09/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER II
THE ROCKY ISLE
For another week or more I remained upon the Blanche waiting till my full strength returned, also because Kari said I must do so. When I asked him why, he replied for the reason that he wished news of my coming to spread far and wide throughout the land from one tribe to another, which it would do with great swiftness, flying, as he put it, like a bird.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#10 Book 2 Ch 3 The Daughter of the Moon - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep10/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep10/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER III
THE DAUGHTER OF THE MOON
For the fourth time since we were cast away on this island the huge full moon shone in a sky of wondrous blue. Kari and I watched it rise between the two snow-clad peaks far away that he had called a gateway to his land, which was so near to us and yet it would seem more distant than Heaven itself. Heaven we might hope to reach upon the wings of spirit when we died, but to that country how could we come?</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#11 Book 2 Ch 4 The Oracle of Rimac - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep11/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep11/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER IV
THE ORACLE OF RIMAC
In this town of Quismancu I remained for seven days, going abroad but little, for when I did so the people pressed about me and stared me out of countenance. There was a garden at the back of the hose surrounded by a wall built of mud bricks. Here for the most part I sat and here the great ones of the place came to visit me, bringing me offerings of robes and golden vessels and I know not what besides.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#12 Book 2 Ch 5 Kari Goes - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep12/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep12/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER V
KARI GOES
As it chanced during the remaining days of that journey, Quilla and I were not again alone together (that is to say, except once for a few minutes), for we were never out of eyeshot of someone in our company. Thus Kari clung to me very closely, indeed, and when I asked him why, told me bluntly that it was for my safety’s sake. A god to remain a god, he said, should live alone in a temple.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#13 Book 2 Ch 6 The Choice - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep13/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep13/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER VI
THE CHOICE
That night I slept but ill who was overwhelmed with all that had befallen me of good and evil. I had gained a wondrous love, but she who gave it was, it seemed, about to be lost to me, aye, and to be thrown to another whom she hated, to forward the dark policies of a great and warlike people. I had spoken to her with high words of hope, but of it in my heart there was little.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#14 Book 2 Ch 7 The Return of Kari - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep14/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep14/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER VII
THE RETURN OF KARI
So Quilla, seated in a golden litter and accompanied by maidens as became her rank, soon was borne away in the train of the Inca Upanqui, leaving me desolate. Before she went, under pretence of bidding me farewell, none denying her, she gained private speech with me for a little while.
“Lord and Lover,” she said, “I go to what fate I know not, leaving you to what fate I know not, and as your lips have said, it is right that I should go.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#15 Book 2 Ch 8 The Field of Blood - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep15/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep15/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER VIII
THE FIELD OF BLOOD
When on the morrow Huaracha, King of the Chancas, heard all this story and that Urco had given poison to his daughter Quilla, who, if she still lived at all, did so, it was said, as a blind woman, a kind of madness took hold of him.
“Now let war come; I will not rest or stay,” he cried, “till I see this hound, Urco, dead, and hang up his skin stuffed with straw as an offering to his own god, the Sun.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#16 Book 2 Ch 9 Kari Comes to his Own - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep16/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep16/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER IX
KARI COMES TO HIS OWN
When I awoke on the following morning in the splendid chamber of which I have spoken, it was to find that my armour and arms had been restored to me, and very glad was I to see Wave-Flame again. After I had eaten and, escorted by servants, walked in the gardens, for never could I be left alone, marvelling at the wondrous golden fruits and flowers, a messenger came to me, saying that the Villaorna desired speech with me.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#17 Book 2 Ch 10 The Great Horror - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep17/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep17/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER X
THE GREAT HORROR
The day of the new moon came and with it the great horror that caused all the Empire of Tavantinsuyu to tremble, fearing lest Heaven should be avenged upon it.
Since Upanqui had found his elder son again he began to dote upon him, as in such a case the old and weak-minded often do, and would walk about the gardens and palaces with his arm around his neck babbling to him of whatever was uppermost in his mind.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#18 Book2 Ch 11 The House of Death - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep18/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep18/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER XI
THE HOUSE OF DEATH
Now at one time during this long war against Urco victory smiled upon him, though afterwards the scale went down against him. Kari was defeated in a pitched battle and I who commanded another army was almost surrounded in a valley. When everything seemed lost, afterwards I escaped by leading my soldiers round up the slope of a mountain and surprising Urco in the rear, but as it ended well for us I need not speak of that matter.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#19 Book 2 Ch 12 The Fight to the Death - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep19/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep19/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER XII
THE FIGHT TO THE DEATH
There was tumult in the hall; shoutings, groans from him whom I had first struck down, the sound of vases and vessels overthrown, and above all those of a woman’s shrieks echoing from the walls and roof, so that I could not tell whence they came.
Through the gross darkness I went on towards the curtains, or so I hoped. Presently they were torn open, and by the faint light of the breaking dawn I saw my eight Chancas rushing towards me.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>#20 Book 2 Ch 13 The Kiss of Quilla - The Virgin of the Sun</title>
        <link>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep20/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://swaggerwords.win/en/the-virgin-of-the-sun-ep20/</guid>
        <description>CHAPTER XIII
THE KISS OF QUILLA
Her women bore Quilla swooning from that ill-fated field, and sick and sad she remained until once more we saw the City of the Chancas. Yet all this while strength and sight were returning to her eyes, so that in the end she could see as well as ever she had done, for which I thanked Heaven.
Messengers had gone before us, so that when we drew near all the people of the Chancas came out to meet us, a mighty multitude, who spread flowers before us and sang songs of joy.</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
